Sigma Xi Records UA201
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Sigma Xi Records
1924 -- 1974
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Sigma Xi, Tufts Chapter
UA201
2.67 Linear Feet 3 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series: Sigma Xi.
Custodial History
This collection was created from an uncataloged photograph found in the stacks in Summer 2008 and relevant folders from the UA024-Activities and Organizations.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains documents related to the founding and running of the Sigma Xi Scientific Research Society, including certificates, correspondence, financial records, membership rosters, minutes, and subject files.
Biographical / Historical
The Tufts College Chapter of the Society of the Sigma Xi was formally installed by the national officers of the society on April 2. The day's activities began with an academic procession and convocation, attended by the Tufts College faculty and student body as well as by the national officers and delegates from chapters in many other institutions. At the convocation exercises Dr. Leonard Carmichael, president of the college and member of Sigma Xi, gave a brief history of scientific research at the college. Dr. George Baitsell, of Yale University, national secretary; Dr. Harlow Shapley, of Harvard University, national president, and Dr. Edward Ellery, of Union College, past national president, were introduced and presented interesting accounts of the growth and aims of the Society of the Sigma Xi.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Student life; Student Activities -- Student Government, Clubs, and Organizations
- Sigma Xi, 1924 -- 1974; 1941 -- 1974; UA201.001; 2.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records related to the founding and running of the Sigma Xi Scientific Research Society.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Sigma Xi: by-laws, 1943 -- 1967; UA201.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Xi: lecture notices, 1941 -- 1958; UA201.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Xi: Manual, 1943 -- 1974; UA201.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Xi, 1924 -- 1974; UA201.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Xi, 1943 -- 1971; UA201.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Xi, 1941 -- 1956; UA201.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Xi, national meetings, 1968 -- 1972; UA201.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Sigma Xi, nominations and memberships, 1941 -- 1962; UA201.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Sigma Xi, nominations and memberships, 1965 -- 1967; UA201.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Sigma Xi, members, 1968 -- 1974; UA201.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Sigma Xi, certificates, 1974; UA201.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Sigma Xi, Installation of Chapter, 1941 -- 1943; UA201.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Charter for the establishment of the chapter of the society of the Sigma Xi at Tufts College, 1943; UA201.001.003.00001 (Box Shared 36)
    This photograph was found uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008. Note its different location; it is housed in a box with other oversize materials.